Our very first project in the self-driving car then will be to find lane markings.
自動運転車における 最初のプロジェクトは 車線の検知でしょう
Why is that important?
なぜ そんなに重要かと 言えば
Well, I can tell you if it can't find lane markings,
車線を 検知できなかったら
you will have no clue where to drive.
どこを走ればいいか わからないからです
You probably don't pay much attention to him,
皆さんは きっと車線に 注意を払っていないでしょう
but as a self-driving car engineer,
でも 自動運転車エンジニアになれば
they'll become your best friend.
すぐに仲良しに なるはずです
They'll tell you a lot as to where to drive. What is Computer Vision?
車線は どこを走るべきか 知らせてくれますコンピュータービジョンとは 何か
When you and I drive a car,
私たちが 車を運転するときは
we use our eyes more than any other organ to understand what to do.
体のどの器官よりも 目を 多く使って 何をすべきか 判断します
Computer Vision does this the same capability into computers.
コンピュータービジョンは それと同じ能力を コンピューターで 実現します
Uses cameras, and we learned how to extract things like
カメラを使い そのカメラ画像から 車線や
lane markings and other vehicles out of camera images,
他の車両などを 抽出する方法を 私たちは 開発しました
it's a lot of fun.
すごく 楽しいですよ
Deep learning has become one of the hottest fields in Silicon Valley,
ディープラーニングは シリコンバレーで 最もホットな分野の 1つになり
and it's now massively been applied to self-driving cars.
自動運転車に 大規模に 利用されています
We're going to train a neural network to find traffic signs and images.
私たちは トレーニングを通じて ニューラルネットワークに 交通標識や 画像を 識別させようとしています
We are here with cloning means that our learning program will copy and
行動クローニングでは 学習プログラムが ステアリング操作や
clone human behavior such as our steering actions and brake and gas actions,
ブレーキ操作 ペダル操作などの 人間行動を 模倣して クローンを作成します
and you get a chance to try it on your own.
これは 皆さんにも 試してもらいます
When we train people,
相手が 人間なら
we don't train them by giving them the rules,
ルールを与えて トレーニングするのではなく
we train by letting them learn from examples.
例を与えて 自分で学習させます
So, in this unit,
そこで このユニットでは
you are going to apply neural networks,
ニューラルネットワーク つまりディープラーニングを
Deep Learning to camera images and do
カメラ画像に適用して 自動運転車に
some of the very things that a self-driving car ought to do right.
実行させたいことを 実行します
I'm really excited to get you to the world of Sensor fusion.
皆さんを センサーフュージョンの世界に 連れて行くのが 楽しみです
What is Sensor fusion? It is the science how to integrate different types of sensors.
センサーフュージョンとは 何かそれは 異なる種類の センサーを 統合する科学です
Self-driving cars have things like LIDARS,
自動運転車は LIDARや
and they have radars,
レーダー そして
and also cameras, and their internal sensors got gyroscopes, inertial measurement units.
カメラを装備し 内蔵センサーには ジャイロスコープや 慣性計測装置が あります
Sensor fusion is a science how to come up
センサーフュージョンとは さまざまな様式から
with a single clear picture based on these different modalities.
1つの 明瞭な画像を 作り上げる科学です
Localization is the simple question where relative to the world is a car.
ローカライゼーションとは 車が 世界との相対で どこにあるかを 特定することです
It's important because as you're going to see,
なぜ重要かと いうと これから 見ていくとおり
you're going to build maps of the environment with lots of detailed information,
膨大な 詳細情報を使って 周囲の地図を 作成するわけですが
some of which might even be invisible to the robot.
そこには ロボットには 見えないものも 含まれます
Like where are the dangers?
どこに 危険が 潜んでいるか
Where do pedestrians typically cross?
歩行者は 道のどこを 渡ることが 多いか
To make sense of those maps,
地図の 意味を 理解するために
the robot must know where it is right from the map.
ロボットは 地図上での 自分の位置を 正確に把握しなければなりません
The alignment of the sensor data,
センサーデータの整合や
the current position to a map,
地図における 現在位置
that's what's called Localization.
それが ローカライゼーションを 構成します
Path planning is the science of how to find
パスプランニングは 迷路の中で 有効なステップや
a valid sequence of steps or actions in a maze.
アクションのシーケンスを 見つけるための科学です
But even in Southern Manhattan for example, you want to cross the city,
たとえば マンハッタン南にいても 町を横断したかったら
and you have to find a plan,
地図を 見つけて
a sequence of street you will go down to make it all the way to the other end.
どの道を たどれば 反対側に 着くか 調べなければなりません
A path planning algorithm is an algorithm that finds that sequence of actions for you.
そういった アクションのシーケンスを パスプランニングアルゴリズムが 見つけてくれるのです
It can apply to city navigation,
都市部でのナビゲーションにも 使えれば
it also applies to parking lot navigation,
たとえば 駐車場内での
for example, across the parking lot.
ナビゲーションにも 使えます
So, now we're entering the fascinating world of what's called control.
次は 制御という とてもおもしろい世界を のぞいてみましょう
In technical terms, what the controller does is
技術的に 言えば 制御とは
a computer program that steers your wheels,
車のステアリングやアクセルペダルそしてブレーキペダルを
your gas pedal, your brake pedal so as to meet a given objective.
与えられた目的に沿って 操作する コンピュータープログラムです
So, for example, if your objective is to stay
たとえば 道路の中央を 走り続けたいとします
centered in the road, and you start driving,
車が走り始めて しばらくすると 左にそれてきます
and your car veers a little bit to the left,
そのとき コントローラーが
your controller is the unit to decide,
「よし ハンドルを 少し右に切って
okay, we compensate with the slight right under the steering wheel.
修正しよう」と 決めるわけです
That might sound trivial,
ささいなことの ように思えますが
but it's really easy to screw it up.
実際には へまを しかねない場面です
So, now we're ready for the most fascinating part of this that I think we will take
これで 最も エキサイティングな ステップに進む 準備ができました
your code onto a physical car and drive it around in California. Sounds scary?
自分のコードを 実際の自動車に 組み込んで カリフォルニアの道路を 走るのですこわいですか?
Yes, I'm slightly scared,
まあ ちょっと こわいですよね
but I'm also really excited because there's no great,
でも 本当に ワクワクします  なぜなら
I don't think that would be complete without actually writing
実際の自動車のために 実際の ソフトウェアを書くことほど
funny actual software for cars. So, let's do it.
完璧な学習方法は 他にありませんからでは やってみましょう